<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mains on Patrice&#39;s favourite recipes</title>
    <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/categories/mains/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mains on Patrice&#39;s favourite recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://patricerecipebook.com/categories/mains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry&#39;s chickpea curry</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/gerry_chickpea_curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/gerry_chickpea_curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 large can of chickpeas drained and rinsed under cold water 3 tablespoons of tomato paste 2 tablespoons olive oil 1 medium onion, finely diced
 2 garlic cloves, minced
 1 tablespoon of fresh minced ginger 400ml vegetable stock
 1.5 teaspoon curry powder 1 teaspoon turmeric 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon ground coriander seed 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon garam masala 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon ground cumin 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon ground ginger 1&amp;frasl;8 teaspoon cinnamon 1&amp;frasl;8 teaspoon ground cloves 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon salt  Directions  Sautée the onion in olive oil until translucent (5-6 minutes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea potato curry</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/chickpea_potato_curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/chickpea_potato_curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 1&amp;frasl;2 cups vegetable broth Two 15­ounce cans chickpeas (garbanzo beans), drained and rinsed One 14 1/2­ ounce can fire­roasted or stewed tomatoes with chiles 2 sweet potatoes cubed 1 medium onion, diced (about 2 cups) 2 Tbsp olive oil 2 teaspoons minced ginger 1­/2 teaspoons salt 2 teaspoons curry 1&amp;frasl;8 to 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon cayenne pepper (to taste)  Directions  In a large pot, heat the olive oil over medium/­high heat and sauté the onions and ginger until the onion begins to brown, about 5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantry dal</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/pantry_dal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/pantry_dal/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 heaping tablespoon (20 mL) virgin coconut oil or olive oil 4 cups peeled (if necessary) and diced veggies* 1&amp;frasl;2 cup (100 g) uncooked red lentils 1&amp;frasl;2 cup (125 mL) water, plus more if needed 1 (14-ounce/398 mL) can diced tomatoes 1 (14-ounce/398 mL) can light coconut milk 1 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoons (7.5 mL) garlic powder 1 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoons (7.5 mL) minced onion** 1 tablespoon (15 mL) good curry powder, or to taste*** 3&amp;frasl;4 to 1 teaspoon fine sea salt, to taste Freshly ground black pepper, to taste  Directions  In a large pot, melt the coconut oil over low-medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef stew</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/beef_stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/beef_stew/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 Large Carrot – Chopped 1 Small Onion – Chopped 4 Large Cloves Garlic – Minced 2 Tbs. Organic Tomato Paste 2 Tbs. Worcestershire Sauce or Coconut Aminos 2 tsp. Sea Salt 1 ½ tsp. Black Pepper 1 tsp. Garlic Powder 1 tsp. Onion Powder 1 tsp. Dried Oregano  Directions No official directions, hopefully you know how to make a stew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and gruyère quiche</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/spinach_and_gruyere_quiche/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/spinach_and_gruyere_quiche/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 9-inch deep dish frozen pie crust 1 tablespoon butter 1&amp;frasl;2 cup thinly sliced shallots 4 large eggs 1-1&amp;frasl;4 cups heavy cream Pinch ground nutmeg 3&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon salt 1&amp;frasl;8 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1 cup grated Gruyère 1 10-ounce package frozen chopped spinach, defrosted and wrung free of water  Directions Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Remove pie crust from freezer and thaw until just soft enough to easily prick with a fork, about 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguine with peppers, artichokes, olives and shrimp</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/linguine_with_peppers_etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/linguine_with_peppers_etc/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 tablespoons olive oil, divided 20 medium shrimp (1&amp;frasl;2 lb.), raw, peeled and deveined 2 thin slices prosciutto cut into thin strips 1 red bell pepper, cut into thin strips ¾ tsp. salt divided plus more for pasta water ¾ tsp. ground black pepper, divided 4 garlic cloves thinly sliced 10 green pitted olives, thickly 1 cup (4 large) canned artichoke hearts, cut into thin wedges 1&amp;frasl;3 cup dry white wine such as Pinot Grigio 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut curry shrimp</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/coconut_curry_shrimp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/coconut_curry_shrimp/</guid>
      <description> Ingredients  1 can coconut milk 1 teaspoon fish sauce 1 tablespoon mild curry powder 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon salt 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon pepper 1 pound thawed peeled deveined raw large shrimp 1 sweet red pepper diced 2 green onions chopped 1&amp;frasl;4 cup cilantro leaves 4 lime wedges  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broccoli quinoa casserole</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/broccoli_quinoa_casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/broccoli_quinoa_casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 1&amp;frasl;2 cups uncooked quinoa 4 1&amp;frasl;2 cups vegetable stock or water 2 tablespoons pesto sauce 2 teaspoons arrowroot powder or cornstarch 2 cups fresh spinach 12 ounces mozzarella cheese 1&amp;frasl;3 cup parmesan cheese 12 ounces fresh broccoli florets 3 green onions  Directions  Preheat the oven to 400F. In a 9x13 baking rectangular dish place the quinoa and green onions. On the meantime, place the broccoli in a large bowl and microwave on high for 4-5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sautéed rainbow chard with raw beets and goat cheese</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/rainbow_chard_with_raw_beets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/rainbow_chard_with_raw_beets/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 to 4 medium-sized beets with the leaves 1 large bunch rainbow chard 1 tablespoon extra-virgin olive oil 4 ounces goat cheese, crumbled  For the dressing:
 2 1&amp;frasl;2 tablespoons balsamic vinegar 1 teaspoon brown sugar 1&amp;frasl;4 cup extra-virgin olive oil Salt and pepper  Directions Chop off the beet greens and set them aside. Peel the beets and either grate them on a box grater or in a food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet potato and quince pie</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/sweet_potato_and_quince_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/main/sweet_potato_and_quince_pie/</guid>
      <description>All butter cornmeal crust:  150 gr all-purpose flour 100 gr fine cornmeal flour 125 sweet butter, torn into small pieces a pinch of salt 1 egg for egg wash  Mix all the ingredients except the egg together, roll out, and place in a deep dish pie pan or terra cotta gratin pan like I use. Make a fluted edge high enough to hold the filling. Brush with egg wash and let dry while preparing the filling</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>