<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>salad on Patrice&#39;s favourite recipes</title>
    <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/categories/salad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in salad on Patrice&#39;s favourite recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://patricerecipebook.com/categories/salad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kale and Quinoa Salad</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/kale_and_quinoa_salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/kale_and_quinoa_salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Marinated Kale:  8 cups (packed) kale leaves (Note 1) 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1/4 tsp each salt and pepper  Quinoa:  1 cup quinoa, any colour 2 cups water  Dressing:  Zest of 1 large lemon 2 1/2 tbsp lemon juice 3 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1 tsp Dijon mustard (or American) 1 garlic clove , minced 1 tsp sugar (optional, I add it) 1/2 tsp each salt and pepper  Salad:  1/4 cup dill leaves , roughly chopped 1/4 cup coriander/cilantro leaves , roughly chopped 1 red onion , quartered and finely sliced (optional) 1/3 - 1/2 cup chopped roasted almonds 100 g crumbled feta  Directions Marinated Kale:  Scrunch up the kale leaves then slice to about 1cm thickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango broccoli salad</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/mango_broccoli_salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/mango_broccoli_salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 cups chopped broccoli 1 large ripe mango, seeded, peeled, &amp;amp; diced 1/2 cup cashews 1 small red onion cut into thin wedges 1/2 cup bottled buttermilk ranch dressing 2 tablespoons orange juice 1 tablespoon horse radish 1 11 ounce can mandarin orange sections drained  Directions In a large bowl, combine broccoli, mango, cashews and onion. For dressing, in a small bowl stir together ranch dressing, orange juice and horse radish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek orzo salad</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/greek_orzo_salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/greek_orzo_salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups uncooked orzo pasta 2 (6 ounce) cans marinated artichoke hearts 1 tomato, seeded and chopped 1 cucumber, seeded and chopped 1 red onion, chopped 1 cup crumbled feta cheese 1 (2 ounce) can black olives, drained 1/4 cup chopped fresh parsley 1 tablespoon lemon juice 1/2 teaspoon dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon lemon pepper Add all ingredients to list  Directions  Bring a large pot of lightly salted water to a boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango bean salad</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/mango_bean_salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/mango_bean_salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 can black beans, drained and rinsed (or 8 oz. dried ones, soaked and boiled) 4 Roma tomatoes 1 red pepper 1 red onion 2 avocados 1 mango 3 oz. fresh parsley (or coriander if you like it) 1 can corn kernels, drained  Dressing:
 2 tablespoons lime juice 1/2 tsp chili powder (or 1 small red chilli pepper, chopped fine) 1 clove garlic (minced or through press) 1/4 cup olive oil (I used less, its not really necessary)  Directions Cut everything up and put it together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry-lentil salad</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/cherry_lentil_salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/cherry_lentil_salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cup dried green (French) lentils, rinsed and picked through 2 tablespoons red wine vinegar, plus more to taste 2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil 1 bunch green onions, sliced 1 teaspoon fine sea salt, plus more to taste 3/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper 4 cups fresh cherries (about 1 pound), pitted and halved 1 cup chopped fresh basil  Directions Combine lentils and 5 cups water in a large saucepan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kale waldorf salad</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/kale_waldorf_salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/salad/kale_waldorf_salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 cups packed finely chopped kale, preferably dinosaur kale 1 large red apple, such as Fuji or Honeycrisp, chopped, divided 3 large celery stalks, thinly sliced 1/2 cup walnuts, toasted and chopped, divided 1/4 cup plus 2 tablespoons raisins, divided 2 tablespoons Dijon mustard 1 tablespoon red wine vinegar 1/8 teaspoon fine sea salt  Directions Place kale in a large bowl. Add half the apple to kale along with celery, 1/4 cup walnuts and 1/4 cup raisins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>