<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Etcs on Patrice&#39;s favourite recipes</title>
    <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Etcs on Patrice&#39;s favourite recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight Blueberry Almond Oats</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/overnight_oats_bleuberry_almond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/overnight_oats_bleuberry_almond/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3&amp;frasl;4 cup large flake oats (yellow Quaker Oats brand bag) 1 tbsp ground flax 2 tbsp almond butter 1 tbsp maple syrup or brown sugar 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp ground cinnamon 1 pinch salt 2 tbsp chopped roasted almonds 3&amp;frasl;4 cup fresh blueberries 1 cup almond or regular milk (we find almond milk adds a nutty flavour)  Directions Combine all ingredients, mix, cover and let sit in the fridge overnight Enjoy in the morning!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cowboy salsa dip</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/cowboy_salsa_dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/cowboy_salsa_dip/</guid>
      <description>Mix together &amp;amp; bring to a boil:
 1&amp;frasl;2 cup olive oil 1&amp;frasl;4 cup white sugar 3&amp;frasl;4 cup apple cider or white vinegar 1 Tablespoon water salt and pepper to taste  Cool and add to mixture below:
 1 cup diced green pepper 1 cup diced red pepper 1 cup onion (preferably red) 1 cup diced celery Cilantro  Chop veggies very fine and mix together in large bowl. Drain, rinse and add to veggies:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kale pesto</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/kale_pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/kale_pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 big bunch of kale, rinsed, ribs removed and torn into large pieces 3&amp;frasl;4 cup EVOO, 2 tablespoons of which was Meyer lemon olive oil 1&amp;frasl;2 cup Parmigiano, microplaned 2 cloves garlic, smashed and rough chopped 1&amp;frasl;2 cup pine nuts Salt and pepper to taste 1 tablespoon lemon juice, fresh  Directions  Blanch the kale in boiling salted water for about 3 minutes and chill down in a cold water bath, drain and squeeze excess water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The best granola</title>
      <link>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/best_granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patricerecipebook.com/etc/best_granola/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 cups old-fashioned rolled oats 2 to 2 1&amp;frasl;2 cups your choice of nuts and seeds* 1 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoons kosher salt 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon cinnamon 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon cardamom 1&amp;frasl;2 cup oil, such as olive oil 1&amp;frasl;2 cup plus 1 tablespoon liquid sweetener, such as honey or maple syrup 3&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon vanilla 3&amp;frasl;4 cup dried fruits, chopped  Equipment  Mixing bowls Measuring cups and spoons Spatula Parchment Half-sheet pan or baking sheet  Directions  Set out your ingredients: For this particular run of granola we are using: 3 cups old-fashioned oats, 1&amp;frasl;2 cup pumpkin seeds, 1&amp;frasl;2 cup sesame seeds, 1&amp;frasl;2 cup almonds, 1&amp;frasl;2 cup wide-flake, unsweetened coconut (added near the end of baking), 1 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon kosher salt, 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon cinnamon, 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon cardamom, 3&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon vanilla extract, 1&amp;frasl;2 cup olive oil, 1&amp;frasl;2 cup + 1 tablespoon maple syrup, 3&amp;frasl;4 cup dried cherries, chopped (added at the end), 1 cup roasted pistachios, chopped (added at the end)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>